<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Textile Makerspace</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="" rel="self"/>
  <link href=""/>
  <updated>2023-06-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu</id>
  <author>
    <name>Quinn Dombrowski</name>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>#DH Makes at ACH 2023</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/dhmakes-at-ach2023/"/>
    <updated>2023-06-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/dhmakes-at-ach2023/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-idea&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2022, the hashtag #DHMakes got some traction on DH Twitter, as a way to celebrate the creativity of the DH community, which is often infused with and shaped by their digital humanities work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ACH 2023, a group of us (Claudia Berger, Quinn Dombrowski, Jojo Karlin, Alix Keener, Anne Ladyem McDivitt, Amanda Visconti, and Jacque Wernimont) got together to attempt an &amp;quot;alternate format&amp;quot; contribution that would create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/dhmakes2023&quot;&gt;virtual curated collection&lt;/a&gt; of making shared across the now-fragmented social media platforms of digital humanities, and also involve a collaborative making project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-collaboration&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had just one synchronous brainstorming session that led to more ideas than we were ultimately able to implement. The group project coalesced around the idea of &amp;quot;DH Scouts&amp;quot;, and a vest with badges on it in the spirit of Girl Scouts. It also had pockets, ideologically, in protest of the widespread absence of functional pockets in &amp;quot;women&#39;s&amp;quot; clothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we crowdsourced suggestions for logos of &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot; DH projects: including tools/infrastructure that had been shut down, projects that were no longer maintained (and/or whose websites had lapsed), and organizations that were defunct. We printed these logos onto fabric and sewed them into a dress for Dr. Cheese Bones (of DH/ACH 2019 fame, and the Textile Makerspace mascot) to wear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dh-animals&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;DH animals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The back of the vest, as well as the pockets, are interpretations of Jojo Karlin&#39;s doodle on the theme of &amp;quot;DH animals&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/dhanimals-doodle.png&quot; alt=&quot;DH animals doodle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(some more prose here about the doodle?)
The images in the doodle have to do with some of the mascots that circulate in digital humanities spaces: Digital Manatees (which began as a curious mishearing of Digital Humanities), the Humanities Commons platypus, the DHSI crow, a Twitter bird communing with a Mastodon. The team brainstormed a peaceable kingdom of curious creatures to complement the activity of DH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Textile Makerspace, Quinn used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/equipment/brother-kh940-knitting-machine/&quot;&gt;Brother KH-940 knitting machine&lt;/a&gt;, recently hacked using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ayab-knitting.com/&quot;&gt;All Yarns Are Beautiful&lt;/a&gt; hardware and software, to render the doodle in knitting, which forms the lower back of the vest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pockets are an automated embroidery design conversion from a SVG version of the doodle. It wasn’t optimized at all in terms of which pieces were embroidered in which order, so there were running threads all over. Those threads were trimmed on one of the pockets, but not the other, for a glitch-art effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;zine-card-deck&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Zine card deck&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pockets are exactly the right size to hold Amanda’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarslab.lib.virginia.edu/blog/themed-reading-list-decks-zines/&quot;&gt;zine card deck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ach-badge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;ACH badge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne Ladyem needle felted an ACH logo, which Quinn sewed (using a decorative leaf stitch) onto a backing and attached it to the vest using Velcro to make the whole piece washable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;quilt&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Quilt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claudia Berger sewed a miniature quilt patch that visualized the top terms in ACH 2023 session titles, with metadata for each section on the backside. Quinn attached it to the vest only at the top, so it can be flipped up for metadata visibility.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/MiniDataQuilt_back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front of the mini data quilt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/MiniDataQuilt_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Back of the mini data quilt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-additions&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Future additions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alix Keener is working on loop fastenings for the vest made out of finger-woven craft loops that will visualize the #DHMakes contributions from across social media during the conference.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/finger_woven_dhmakes.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example of a finger-woven rope with brightly colored craft loops&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-model&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cheese Bones modeled the outfit, requiring an arm-socket repair in the process.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/cheese-vest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dr. Cheese bones wearing the vest next to a sign that reads ‘I want to make beautiful things even if nobody cares’&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/cheese-vest-back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dr. Cheese Bones wearing the vest, with the knitted part showing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/dhmakes2023/cheese-repair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quinn repairs Cheese with a hot glue gun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-together%2C-at-a-distance&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Making together, at a distance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to our one synchronous Zoom call, we had an ongoing email thread where we kept in touch with updates, images, and words of encouragement. Seeing each other’s pieces as they were completed helped motivate us to finish our pieces, as well as to confirm where/when to mail them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vest will likely take on a life as a traveling object, accruing new adornments along the way. Look for it at a future virtual or in-person DH conference!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hong Kong University &#39;New Horizons in DH&#39; Textile Data Visualization</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/hku-new-horizons-dataviz/"/>
    <updated>2023-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/hku-new-horizons-dataviz/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-idea&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdt.arts.hku.hk/newdhcds&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Horizons in Digital Humanities &amp;amp; Cultural Data Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; workshop at Hong Kong University, organized by Javier Cha, brought together experts in digital humanities and data science from around the world for a week of lectures and hands-on sessions on topics ranging from text annotation to multilingual text analysis to GIS and conspiracy theory networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before the workshop started, there was a day trip to Macau, which I had written my elementary school country report on and had always wanted to visit. I&#39;d been planning a lunchtime textile data viz workshop, and had brought with me my Addi circular knitting machine along with a bunch of assorted yarn, but I didn&#39;t have a plan for what we&#39;d make. That changed in a little cafe most of the way up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortaleza_do_Monte&quot;&gt;Fortaleza do Monte&lt;/a&gt;, where fellow instructors Gimena del Rio Riande and Melanie Walsh were discussing their travel routes to get to Hong Kong while we picked up bottles of water and enjoyed some AC. It occurred to me that the space and time of transit was a shared experience for everyone at the workshop, local or visitor, and we could represent both together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gimena&#39;s talk on &amp;quot;Humanidades Digitales: A Low-Tech Approach to Digital Humanities&amp;quot;, on the first day of the workshop, literally gave shape to the map component of the piece by reminding me of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dymaxion_map&quot;&gt;Dymaxion map&lt;/a&gt; I made for the ill-fated &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200323100809/http://arounddh.org/&quot;&gt;Around DH 2020&lt;/a&gt;. By the time I held the textile data viz workshop at lunchtime that day, I had a plan to share: we&#39;d fill in a survey about how long it took us to get here. That data would be a knitted rectangular base for the visualization. On top, I&#39;d use yarn to embroider a world map (Dymaxion projection) as well as a Hong Kong map, and we&#39;d add in people&#39;s actual routes to get to Hong Kong University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-dymaxion-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gimena&#39;s presentation with the Dymaxion map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sent out a survey later that day, with a deadline of the following day. We got 35 responses, and we added to that the 32 Zoom participants from the first day&#39;s session. For being a free-text field, the data wasn&#39;t too messy; most people answered in minutes or hours. I decided to exclude the one response that read &amp;quot;3 years&amp;quot;; I suppose &amp;quot;getting here&amp;quot; was potentially vague enough to include a more metaphorical understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a few tries to cluster the responses down to a number of buckets that corresponded to the different yarns I had on hand. I also wanted the visualization to be roughly 100 rows of knitting; doing one per piece of data would only get me 2/3 of the way there. So I converted the responses to percentages instead of raw numbers (which I often recommend when you&#39;ve got data that&#39;s either bigger or smaller than you want it to be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-percents.png&quot; alt=&quot;Table showing raw responses, percents, and colors for the data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gimena helped me pick out which colors would correspond to which data ranges. From there, I measured out each color yarn and tied it together into a data ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-gimena-databall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gimena helping pick out yarns, and the data ball that resulted&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a demo of how to use the Addi circular knitting machine to do flat knitting, but the flat knitting is a little more challenging than circular knitting, especially for beginners. I&#39;d hoped to have participants knit the real data, but ran out of time and ended up doing it myself in the evening. Even I struggled a little with flat knitting on the machine, and ended up having several dropped stitches and holes to patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-data-knitting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jodie Cheng trying the circular knitting machine, and knitting the actual data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-maps&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The maps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embroidery is not a textile method I use a lot, and I&#39;ve struggled with it before. I also struggle with drawing, leading me to conclude that I really needed to not attempt freehand map embroidery. Student assistants printed out copies of the two maps for me at roughly the right size, and I cut them out and tried to embroider around the shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-worldmap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cut out Dymaxion projection world map pieces and attempting to embroider around them&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base material created by the knitting machine introduced challenges. Cutting out the paper shapes already forced some simplification of the images (goodbye, complex coastlines!) but sometimes there just weren&#39;t enough knitted stitches to be able to render even those simplified shapes. I&#39;d used a fairly fine yarn (rainbow-colored, representing Zoom participants), but the problem is that the circular knitting machine only has one needle gauge, optimized for thicker yarns. Several times when I was trying to render a shape, I&#39;d realize I was stitching into the same hole I&#39;d just stitched out of, undoing the previous stitch instead of creating a new one. The result was almost like a new projection, shaped by the materiality of its substrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-worldmap-stitches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Just the outline of the world map embroidered on the yarn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;points-on-the-map&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Points on the map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started off using red pony beads for all the airports, but soon realized I&#39;d run out of red pony beads and would have to switch to orange. (I&#39;d brought various shades of red and orange, plus pink sparkles, with me on the trip; they&#39;re the least popular colors corresponding to angry/negative feelings on this year&#39;s Textile Makerspace sign-in loom.) It actually worked out to have orange as points of origin, and red as points of transfer. If a point was both origin for someone and transfer for someone else, it defaulted to orange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-red-beads-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The original version of the map, with all red beads&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attaching the beads left me reflecting on the challenges of GIS, and things like questions of precision when geocoding data. If you think geocoding a city name is bad (it&#39;ll just put you in the center of the city, which is almost certainly what you actually want), try representing an airport using a pony bead on a loosely-knit textile with an embroidered rendering of a map in an unusual projection. Suffice it to say, the East Coast feels very crowded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beads also pushed the boundaries of the map and further distorted things; I transferred through Manila, which realistically should&#39;ve been somewhere off the edge of the knitting. I put it on the edge instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong airport was indicated with a pink sparkly bead on the international map, and on the Hong Kong map. Hong Kong University also got a pink sparkly bead, as it was the location of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracing-paths&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Tracing paths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already asked for the speakers&#39; international flight path, and began by embroidering those on the world map. Gimena&#39;s route from Argentina to Brazil to Ethiopia involved the longest piece of path-yarn, which became a bit loose the way I tied it to the knitting. Maybe there&#39;s something in there about the way time drags on when flying across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d decided to use turquoise for flight paths, which meant we&#39;d need other colors for other types of travel. Over lunch, I went around asking people for their routes, and orienting them to the Hong Kong map I&#39;d attempted to embroider. I used a darker blue for MTR (subway) transit, which was the most common among the locals. There were several walking paths that were so short I used a single (rather than plied yarn) for those. Yellow was bus, and pink was car (one each). One participant leaned into having complex data, using one means of transit to drop off his daughter, and another to go from her school to the workshop; we tied two colors of yarn together, and put the knot in the center of the path. He took a picture to share with his daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-complex-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A participant with a complex path captured in textiles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;metadata&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Metadata&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post serves as the documentation for what everything on the textile data viz means, but I wanted to put a label on it so people in the future might have some sense at least of what event it corresponded to. So, once again braving the waters of embroidery, I attempted to write &amp;quot;HKU New Horizons 2023&amp;quot; on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-final-visualization&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The final visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-final.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The final visualization, in its entirety and close up&quot; /&gt;
Here&#39;s the final visualization, in its entirety and with a close-up of the two sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just for fun, here&#39;s the backside of data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-data-backside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The backside of the textile data viz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And me with the data viz, and the workshop&#39;s real-world Instagram frame:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-instagram.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Instagram frame and data viz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus%3A-material-afterlives&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Bonus: Material afterlives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got too many souvenirs in Hong Kong and needed to bring a lot less yarn home with me, so I made (non-data) scarves to thank the student assistants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hku-leftovers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7 scarves made with leftover yarn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also made one data scarf using color data, as a thank you present for Jodie Cheng who showed us around for some authentic souvenir shopping in the Sham Shui Po area on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-jodie-scarf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Color data scarf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from the bottom left and working up, then down the other column, the colors represent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colorful fabrics in the Sham Shui Po textile area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hk-fabric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hong Kong fabric market&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainbow children&#39;s toy stands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-cats-childrenstoys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cats on toys at a children&#39;s toy stand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronics shops in the basement (and all the dongles and wires)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hk-electronics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Electronics stands in Hong Kong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Mong Kok (&amp;quot;Bustling Corner&amp;quot;) MTR sign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-mong-kok.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mong Kok MTR sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown sandwiches with green pandan paste at lunch at Semua Semua&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-pandan-sandwich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pandan sandwiches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orange noodles (not pictured) at lunch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turquoise green rice at lunch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-green-rice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Green rice and brown meat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue cyanotype prints of Lion Rock at a souvenir stand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-cyanotype.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyanotype print of Lion Rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shiny metal and glass mall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hk-mall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shiny metal and glass mall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purple seats on the bus back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-purple-seats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Purple seats on a bus with different color bars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White boba (I got lychee with cheese foam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog-hk-boba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lychee with cheese foam boba in a cup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tie dye day</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/tie-dye-05-02-2023/"/>
    <updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/tie-dye-05-02-2023/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite some uncooperative cloudy and rainy weather the Textile Makerspace attempted a tie-dye pop-up in the courtyard of Pigott Hall on May 2nd. We&#39;ll try again when it&#39;s closer to summer and the vibes are better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_shirtdyeing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tie-dying shirts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_shirtresult.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Resulting tie-dyed shirts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>PhD Quilt</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/phdquilt/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/phdquilt/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-final.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PhD quilt visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;context&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made this data visualization PhD quilt in 2013 when my husband, Andy, graduated with a dual PhD in linguistics and Slavic linguistics. I had been sewing for 3 years at that point (only with wovens), and had never done anything quilt-like before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My husband&#39;s dissertation was on phonological contact, particularly between Slavic and non-Slavic languages. At the point when I was making this visualization, he had decided to be done with academia and pursue something in the biomedical field. I wanted this to be a tribute to everything he had done, in the context of what he was planning to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 15, 2013, I was trying to sort out numbers to quantify his time in the PhD program in various ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1 marriage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 dissertation (6 chapters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 QP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exams (9 total)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 ling masters exams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Slavic PhD exams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classes (50)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching (6 taught, 25 lectureships)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st year Russian - 5x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian Through Pushkin - 6x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4th year Russian - 9x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2nd year Russian - 1x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;South Slavic I &amp;amp; II - 2x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language drills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian Through Pushkin - 3x (head of Pushkin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2nd year Russian - 3x (borscht)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4th year Russian - 3x (border of Soviet Union)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st year BCS - 6x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2nd year BCS - 6x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing intern (2 classes, 8 total)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language and the Human - 5x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Being and Citizen - 3x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages taken (13)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BCS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Albanian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macedonian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulgarian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turkish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uzbek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Georgian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old Turkic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chechen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aromanian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publications (11)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellowships (2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whiting Dissertation Fellowship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Century Fellowship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talks and presentations (34 + Slavic Forum)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 departments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 summer seminars (Albanian, Macedonian, medieval Slavic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-design&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was more data than I could reasonably squeeze into a quilt of the size I imagined. So I had to narrow it down to what seemed like the most important things, and then map them to elements of the design. I don&#39;t remember how I/we came up with the design idea, but I have these notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 rays off sun for 6 chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ball of sun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;publications &amp;amp; conference papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;earth/rocks for courses, languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teaching is sky?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below that, a break in the notes, and a sketch I think Andy made:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/phdquilt_design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sketch design for the PhD quilt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dissertation = sun + 6 chapters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11 publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;34-35 talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching = sky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 classes, 25 lectureships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 drills - 24 sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 writing internships, 8 total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exams (9) = water&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classes taken (50) = rocks&lt;/strong&gt;
Here the notes look like I was trying to roughly calculate what size the rocks should be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10&amp;quot; high (+ extra), 36&amp;quot; wide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 extras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48 / 4 = 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;less than 1 high, more than 3 wide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages learned (13) = grass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-colors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers of fabric pieces in each zone of the design represented one set of things (as described above), but the colors and actual fabric design for each zone had a different symbolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slavia Orthodoxa (green/grass)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text-based&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Church_Slavonic&quot;&gt;Old Church Slavonic&lt;/a&gt; Bible quote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birch_bark_manuscript#Old_Slavonic_script&quot;&gt;Birchbark letters&lt;/a&gt; (note: the birchbark letter I used was &lt;a href=&quot;http://gramoty.ru/birchbark/document/show/novgorod/605/&quot;&gt;#605&lt;/a&gt;, an excerpt from which is on our wedding rings)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-medieval.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Green Slavic design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turkish (blue/water)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ottoman poetry / calligraphy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-turkish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Turkish design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albanian (yellow / sun)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mashup of less-well-known alphabets witha good text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One text, many alphabets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-albanian-color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow Albanian design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Slavic (gray / rocks)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latin / Cyrillic font, trilingual text (BCS, Macedonian, Bulgarian)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple texts, single combined alphabet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-sslavic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South Slavic design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evolution / language contact / language change (gradient / sky)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mashup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phonology / IPA (International Phonetic Alphabet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution, adaptive landscape, bio reference TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbolic of language contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was the most challenging to render, as you might guess from the vague notes. There were 5 versions of the double helix design, which is what we settled on for the &amp;quot;bio reference TBD&amp;quot;. We ended up using a variety of different scripts for T/C/A/G on the double helix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyrillic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Georgian a, t, ts, g (ejectives)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devanagari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arabo-persian t, emphatic t; k g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek (alpha, tao, kappa, gamma)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glagolitic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;medieval Cyrillic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, version 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, version 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, version 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, version 4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, version 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the sky was going to be a gradient (to represent the sunset on an academic career, and the sunrise on a biomedical career), I created a final design that would have the double helix in different colors depending on the color of the background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-dhelix-final.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Double helix design, final&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-final-fabric&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The final fabric&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put together a final design that was 42&amp;quot; wide (the max printing width for woven fabrics on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spoonflower.com/&quot;&gt;Spoonflower&lt;/a&gt;) and 108&amp;quot; long (3 yards), with enough of each fabric design for me to cut out the necessary number of pieces. (Want to see the full resolution version in all its detail? &lt;a href=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-final.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here for a PDF&lt;/a&gt;).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-finalfabric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final dissertation project fabric&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cutting-and-sewing&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Cutting and sewing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have one photo of me working on this project: chopping up the gray rocks fabric.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-cutting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting up fabric for the dissertation quilt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the back of the piece, it&#39;s apparent how very &amp;quot;winging it&amp;quot; the whole thing was, cutting and sewing approximations that I hoped would work well enough... and sewing things with more or less seam allowance on the fly when they weren&#39;t working out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/dissertation-back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final dissertation project fabric&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened-next&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What happened next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sides were... not straight. Certainly not straight enough that I could finish them easily, without completely losing some of the fabric pieces that were important for the counts. The sun ball did not lay flat, and was curved and sort of puffy regardless of what I did with it. Also, our first kid was born in November 2013, so soon after this project I became preoccupied with baby stuff. It went into a closet. Then was moved to another closet when we moved to our current house three years later. I forgot about it altogether, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But teaching &lt;em&gt;Data Visualization with Textiles&lt;/em&gt; gave me a chance to revisit it, and you know, I&#39;m now going to figure out a way to hem it, even if I have to pad out the edges a bit. And I&#39;m going to hang it up. It meant a lot to me and my husband that I rediscovered this in the depths of the fabric closet, and now I feel proud of it as the beginning of something I didn&#39;t even recognize as being a thing at the time. There are things in our lives that are these recurring themes, that echo in different ways at different times. For me, I think &lt;em&gt;textiles + data viz&lt;/em&gt; is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Yarn donations from Mary Prada Dombrowski</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/yarn-donations-mary-prada-dombrowski/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/yarn-donations-mary-prada-dombrowski/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An incredible donation of many boxes of yarn brought together Textile Makerspace staff and visitors for a yarn party. Mary Prada Dombrowski delighted students with a gorgeous and diverse assortment of yarns, which were immediately put to good use through knitting and crochet projects. These special yarns are in their own plastic tubs in the Makerspace, and all are welcome to use them -- just send Quinn a picture of what you make, so our generous donor can enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_yarnparty1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Students opening boxes of yarn at the Makerspace&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_yarnparty2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Students opening boxes of yarn at the Makerspace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace renovation complete</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-renovation-complete/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-renovation-complete/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After 9 months of off-and-on work as time, funding, and energy permitted, the Textile Makerspace renovation is finally complete, with the re-hanging of the whiteboard upon the wall! We&#39;re grateful to the whole TAPS crew who have helped, but most of all Heather Patterson Miller, the architect for this entire vision of transforming the Makerspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_kyoheather.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kyo and Heather after hanging up the whiteboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Needle felting pop-up at library exhibit on food</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/needle-felting-popup-food/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/needle-felting-popup-food/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.stanford.edu/exhibitions/special-unique-and-rare-food-green-library-hohbach-hall&quot;&gt;Special, Unique, and Rare exhibit&lt;/a&gt; at the Library had the theme of food, so the Textile Makerspace hosted a hands-on activity for needle felting food (or anything else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staff and grad students alike seemed to find needle felting to be a pleasingly cathartic craft activity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_stabbysign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sign for the pop-up with an add-on sign reading &amp;quot;Feeling STABBY?&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_alstabbing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anne Ladyem works on needle felting a sphere&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Kicking off DLCL 203: Data Visualization with Textiles</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/data-visualization-textiles-2023/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/data-visualization-textiles-2023/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spring quarter kicks off the first-ever class of DLCL 203: Data Visualization with Textiles. In this independent study, students can come by the Textile Makerspace during any of its open hours to learn from staff (or practice on their own) textile-related tools and methods, with the goal of creating a project that incorporates data in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quinn&#39;s experimental project will be to create a toy data set of transcribed and annotated &lt;em&gt;Calvin and Hobbes&lt;/em&gt; comics, looking at different ways to visualize that data in yarn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_crochet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quinn practicing crochet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Visit to the Digital Justice Lab</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/digital-justice-lab-visit/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/digital-justice-lab-visit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of a retreat for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://datasittersclub.github.io/site&quot;&gt;Data-Sitters Club&lt;/a&gt;, Textile Makerspace director Quinn Dombrowski visited Prof. Jacque Wernimont&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitaljusticelab.com/about/&quot;&gt;Digital Justice Lab&lt;/a&gt; at Dartmouth, and was inspired by Molly Morin&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mollymorin.com/knitlab/&quot;&gt;KnitLab&lt;/a&gt; project there. A KH-940 digital knitting machine may be coming soon to the Textile Makerspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_knitlab.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A digital image being knitted on a hacked KH-940 digital knitting machine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Makerspace Annex impacted by flood</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/makerspace-annex-flood/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/makerspace-annex-flood/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A faulty water fountain on the 3rd floor of Pigott Hall led to collapsed ceiling tiles on the 1st floor of the building, including the newly-renamed Textile Makerspace Annex AKA Quinn&#39;s office. The 1960&#39;s LeClerc Mira loom, which had barely been in the room for a week, bore the brunt of the mushy ceiling tiles, but thanks to some quick work and advocacy on the part of DLCL facilities manager John Richardson, we don&#39;t expect it will sustain significant permanent damage.  Many thanks, too, to the making@stanford folks who came over to lend a hand with saving the loom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_loomdrying.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loom underneath collapsed ceiling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace at Library &#39;Technology&#39; pop-up exhibit</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-at-technology-popup/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-at-technology-popup/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Textile Makerspace brought its loom and knitting machines to Hohbach Hall for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2023/03/special-unique-and-rare-technology-march-7&quot;&gt;Special, Unique and Rare: Technology&lt;/a&gt; pop-up exhibit, giving visitors a chance to try out this textile technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_techpopup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Setup for the pop-up event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>LeClerc Mira counterbalance loom comes to the Textile Makerspace</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/leclerc-mira-loom/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/leclerc-mira-loom/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Newly arrived at the Textile Makerspace is a 45&amp;quot; ~1960s vintage LeClerc Mira counterbalance loom, which was so wide it had to be partially disassembled to get through the door. The loom is the first piece of equipment to be stationed in the newly-renamed Textile Makerspace Annex, previously known as Quinn&#39;s office, on the first floor of Pigott Hall (260-108).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_miraloom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mira loom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace celebrates data and textiles at the Love Data Week Fair</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/love-data-week-2023/"/>
    <updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/love-data-week-2023/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Textile Makerspace participated in the Love Data Week Fair on Valentine&#39;s Day, with a station dedicated to textiles and data. As part of the event, we surveyed library staff, followers on Mastodon and on Twitter, and people who attended the event in-person on their feeling about data. At the end of the event, we knitted everyone&#39;s results from a yarn &amp;quot;data ball&amp;quot; into a &amp;quot;data scarf&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of the CIDR staff who helped run the station were wearing matching shirts with Data from &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;/em&gt;, sewed together at the Textile Makerspace. Stanford Digital Repository staff also handed out Valentines created at the Textile Makerspace using our Cricut Make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_ldw2023.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Data and textiles station&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_ldwdataball.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Knitting the data ball&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace hosts a blanket-making volunteer activity</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/blanket-volunteer-activity/"/>
    <updated>2023-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/blanket-volunteer-activity/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Textile Makerspace hosted a Hands-On Bay Area no-sew blanket-making volunteer activity on February 2nd, with optional additional embroidery or appliqué for those inspired to do so. The blankets will be donated to local shelters for our unhoused neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_blanketmaking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Volunteers making blankets&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_llamaapplique.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Llama appliqué&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace gets a Brother KX-350 knitting machine</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/brother-kx350/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/brother-kx350/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a generous gift from Ryan Lieu from Stanford Libraries&#39; Preservation group, the Textile Makerspace now has a Brother KX-350 knitting machine! Come by to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_kx350.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brother KX-350 knitting machine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>making@stanford grant for the Textile Makerspace</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/making-stanford-grant/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/making-stanford-grant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are excited to share the news that the Textile Makerspace has received one of the pilot making@stanford grants, as part of a joint proposal with &lt;em&gt;Miller Makers&lt;/em&gt; (at the Hopkins Marine Station) and the &lt;em&gt;Terman MakerBar&lt;/em&gt; (in the engineering library)! We intend to use most of the funds to hire student staff to help keep the Makerspace open more hours, and more student-friendly hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace at the Library&#39;s Textiles Pop-Up</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textiles-popup/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textiles-popup/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Textile Makerspace held a hands-on pop-up event as part of Stanford Libraries &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2022/10/special-unique-and-rare-textiles-and-fashion-nov-8&quot;&gt;Special, Unique and Rare: Textiles and Fashion&lt;/a&gt; event in Hohbach Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We brought perler beads and had patterns from vintage weaving manuals on hand, giving participants a chance to recreate the weaving patterns (or anything else they&#39;d like) through the medium of perler beads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_perlerbeads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perler beads and weaving patterns&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace welcomes David Wrisley</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/david-wrisley-visit/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/david-wrisley-visit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 21st, digital humanities scholar and multilingual DH activist David Wrisley visited the Textile Makerspace from NYU Abu Dhabi, reuniting with Dr. Cheese Bones, the Textile Makerspace skeleton who won the award for most innovative poster at the DH 2019 conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_wrisley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David Wrisley, Cheese Bones, and Quinn Dombrowski&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace at the JEDI fair</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-jedi-fair-2022/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-jedi-fair-2022/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, the Textile Makerspace had a station at the Stanford Libraries &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice_equity_diversity_and_inclusion_jedi_fair_8413&quot;&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/a&gt;, with the guestbook loom giving visitors a place to express how they were feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_jedifair2022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Textile Makerspace guestbook loom at the JEDI fair&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Friendship bracelet workshop</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/friendship-bracelet-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/friendship-bracelet-workshop/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On September 28th, Alix Keener led a workshop on creating friendship bracelets. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecraftingchicks.com/jellyfish-friendship-bracelets/&quot;&gt;jellyfish friendship bracelet&lt;/a&gt; was especially popular, using a cardboard wheel cut out by our Cricut Make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_alixfriendshipbracelet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alix shows off a friendship bracelet&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_friendshipbraceletstudents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Students working on friendship bracelets&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_friendshipbracelet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friendship bracelets on cardboard wheels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Textile Makerspace reopens</title>
    <link href="https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-reopens/"/>
    <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/blog/textile-makerspace-reopens/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After being closed since March 2020, the Textile Makerspace is officially reopening for fall quarter! Come by our space in Pigott Hall (260-238), where we&#39;ve got plenty of new things to explore, including an embroidery machine! Don&#39;t forget to sign in with our new guestbook loom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://textilemakerspace.stanford.edu/assets/images/blog_reopening.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A skeleton holding the guestbook loom underneath a Textile Makerspace sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>

